(綱手)早かったな。
That was fast...
緊急に… とのことでしたので。
I heard it was a matter of urgency...
お前には カカシの代行を
やってもらう。
I want you to take Kakashi's place.
あの カカシ先輩の代行とは
光栄ですね。
It's an honor to be able to work
in Kakashi-senpai's stead...
これは 暗部としての任務ではなく
通常の任務となる。
This isn't an Anbu Black Ops mission.
It will be a regular mission.
(綱手)よって 面をはずし
コードネームをつける。
Therefore, take off that mask
and I will give you a codename.
その間は 名を 「ヤマト」と名乗れ。
During this mission,
you'll be known as "Yamato".
…わかりました。
I understand.
もう一人… あの暗部養成部門
「根」から 新人が一人➡
An additional member... a new recruit
from the Anbu Black Ops Training Division
will be dispatched to Team Kakashi.
カカシ班に 配属される。
(ヤマト)「根」… からですか？
From... The Foundation?
(綱手)ただ…。
なんです？
However...
What is it?
ソイツの行動には 注意を払っておけ。
Keep a close watch
on his actions.
(サクラ)ナルト… アンタ 知り合いなの？
Naruto, do you know him?
(ナルト)あぁ… コイツは さっき
シカマルたちと一緒にいたとき➡
Yeah...
He's the guy who
attacked me earlier
when I was with Shikamaru
and the others!
襲ってきたヤツだってばよ！
(ヤマト)やめるんだ ナルト君。
Stop it, Naruto-kun!
Come to think of it, who're you, mister?
そういや… おっさん 誰？
Oh... could it be...?
もしかして…。
カカシさんの入院中 この班の隊長を
代行する者だ。
I'm the replacement captain
for this team
while Kakashi-san is in the hospital.
ヤマト と呼んでくれ。
(サクラ)ヤマト隊長…。
Call me Yamato.
Captain... Yamato...
キミたちは 同じ班の仲間なんだから
仲よくしてくれなきゃ困るよ。
You're comrades on the same team,
so you guys need to get along.
な… 仲間って…。
C-Comrade...? This guy?
コイツが!?
(サイ)さっきは ごめんよ。
Sorry about before.
(サイ)これから
同じ班の仲間になる人の➡
Since we're going to be
teammates from now on,
I just wanted to find out
how strong you were.
実力を知っておきたかったんだ。
…だったら わざわざ
あんなこと しなくたって。
You didn't have to go through
the trouble of doing that...
おかげで チンチンついてるかどうかも
疑わしい ヘナチョコだって➡
But thanks to that,
I now know you're a worthless guy
with a questionable dick.
わかったし…。
Hey, what did you say?!
なんだと こら～っ!!
ちょっ… これから➡
- We're going to be teammates!
- Damn you!
仲間になるんだから いきなり
ケンカしないでよっ!!
- Don't start fighting right at the start!
- Some things are inexcusable!
But you're kind of a rotten guy,
aren't you...?
でも… ちょっと アンタ
感じ悪いわね。
アハハ… そうですか？
Is that so?
People won't like you if
you say stuff like that.
(サクラ)そんなことじゃ
嫌われるわよ。
ボクは 好きですよ。
あなたのような➡
I like nice...
women like you who are ugly.
感じのいい ブス。
ブ…。
"Ug-"
(サクラ)なんだと こら～っ!!
(ヤマト)キミ！ 今 ナルト君に➡
Hey, what did you say?!
- Try repeating that, you twerp.
- Hey,
- do you remember what you just said to Naruto-kun?!
- Don't try being cocky with me, Shannaro!
なんて言ったか 覚えてる!?
(自来也)お～ぉ…
しまりのない顔しおって。
Oh, don't you look silly.
Jiraiya-sama.
(カカシ)自来也様…。
Well, I guess you always
looked like that...
(自来也)まっ しまりのないのは
前からか…。
(自来也)聞いたぞ。 １週間は
ベッドの上だそうだな。
I heard you'll be in bed...
for a week, huh?
(カカシ)
まぁ そういうことみたいです…。
Well, it seems so...
(カカシ)うっ…。
おいおいおい… ムリはするな。
Hey, don't force yourself.
こりゃ 当分 動くのは
ムリそうだの…。
It doesn't look like
you'll be able to move for awhile...
It's a get-well gift.
(自来也)見舞いだ！
(自来也)『イチャイチャ パラダイス 豪華版』
上下２巻。
Both volumes of the deluxe edition
of "Make-Out Paradise".
(自来也)
何度か読んだかもしれんが➡
You may have already read
it several times,
but it should at least help
pass the time.
退屈しのぎぐらいには
なるだろう。
どうも…。
Thanks...
まさか このためだけに
里に戻ってきたわけじゃ➡
Surely this isn't the only reason
why you returned to the village.
ないですよね？
まぁ 細かい話は 綱手と…➡
I'll give you the details once he...
and Tsunade get here...
アイツが来てからでいい。
(カカシ)アイツ… 誰です？
He? Who's that?
たしか 今回の任務では 「ヤマト」と
名乗ると 言うとったな…。
I think he's calling himself Yamato
on this mission...
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forgotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenain deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
EVERDAY hereafter is a shining day.
everyday kono saki mo shining day
Unchanging singin', a bright morning smile.
kawarazu singin' hikaru asa no smile
This is the last farewell on funny days.
kore de miosame no funny days
Leaping into the future I see. Go far, dream of my heart.
tobidatsu future mezashita go far kokoro no dream of
I'll go the distance, the endless sky is blue.
i'll go the distance mihatenu sora wa blue
I've hitched a ride on the star ship, this is the best forever trip.
norikonda star ship kore ga saigo no forever trip
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenai deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah, it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
Thank you my friend.
thank you my friend
Ah even now,
aa ano hi no koto
I still remember that day.
ima demo mada oboeteru kara
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah those days that will never come back.
aa mou nidoto sou modoranai days
Woah I'll go the distance!
woah i'll go the distance
An Unnecessary Addition
(ヤマト)とにかく
これから４人で➡
At any rate, the four of us
will be starting our mission now.
すぐ任務に 入ることになる
っていうのに➡
And yet...
なんだ これ？
What's up with this?
(ヤマト)同じ オリに入れて
慣らしてる時間なんかないよ。
I don't have time to put you all in
a cage to get used to each other.
(ヤマト)ほら 自己紹介！
Come on, introduce yourselves.
うずまき ナルト。
Uzumaki Naruto.
春野 サクラです。
I'm Haruno Sakura.
サイと言います。
My name is Sai.
(ヤマト)まぁ とにかく
顔合わせは これで終わり。
Well, that's enough getting
acquainted for now.
(ヤマト)これから ボクら
カカシ班の任務を説明する。
I will now explain our mission
as Team Kakashi.
これより 我々 ４名は
天地橋を 目指し➡
The four of us will now head
for the Tenchi Bridge...
capture the Akatsuki spy who
has infiltrated Orochimaru's organization...
大蛇丸の組織に 潜入している
「暁」のスパイを拘束し➡
連れ帰る。
and bring him back here.
(ヤマト)大蛇丸と うちは サスケの
情報が 手に入る チャンスだ。
It's an opportunity for us
to get information
on Orochimaru and Uchiha Sasuke.
大蛇丸暗殺と サスケ奪取の
両方の作戦を 立案できる➡
We will obtain a precious source
of information
with which we can draw up plans
for both the assassination of Orochimaru
貴重な情報源を
入手することになる。
and the retrieval of Sasuke.
(ヤマト)心して かかるように。
Be sure to proceed with caution!
おう！
はい！
Right!
Yes, sir!
今から １時間後に
正門に 集合！
We'll meet at the main gate
in an hour!
忍具を 調えたのち
出発する！
We'll leave once you've equipped
yourselves with your Ninja tools!
ったく…。
For crying out loud!
あの サイって野郎
気に食わねえってばよ！
I don't like that Sai jerk at all!
なんで サスケの代わりが
アイツなんだよ！
Why's he taking the place of Sasuke?
カカシ班は ３人で
十分だってのに…。
Team Kakashi's fine with
three people!
He does indeed have a foul mouth...
確かに 口は 悪いけど
サイって どことなく➡
but don't you think he kind
of resembles Sasuke-kun?
サスケ君に
似てると 思わない？
顔とか もの言いとか…。
Like his face and the way he talks...
ふんっ！
全然 似てねえってばよ！
He doesn't resemble him at all!
サスケのほうが
かっこいい！
Sasuke's cooler...
No, not cooler.
…じゃなかった。
Well, he's better!
マシだってばよ。
そうね サスケ君のほうが サイより
ちょっと かっこいいよね！
Yeah. Sasuke-kun's a little cooler
than Sai, isn't he?
ちょっとじゃ ねえってばよ！
Not just a little!
Sasuke's totally b-better!
サスケのほうが 全然
マッ マシだってばよ！
Good move.
いい動きだ！
いいか？
いつ何時も 気を抜くな。
Listen carefully...
Never let your guard down.
(サイ)なんです 先輩？
What is it... Senpai?
Listen carefully.
いいか。
お前に 与えられた➡
The classified mission
you've been given is Danzo-sama's...
極秘任務は
ダンゾウ様の…。
猫か…。
A cat, huh...?
とにかく お前に
与えられた 極秘任務は➡
Anyway, Danzo-sama's vision...
for the future of the village rests
upon this classified mission.
里の行く先を 見据えた
ダンゾウ様の意思を担うものだ。
Failure is not an option.
失敗は 許されぬ。
わかっています。
I know.
よし…。
Good.
お前 まだ そんなものを
持ち歩いていたのか？
You're still carrying that
around with you...?
This is...
これは…。
「根」には 名前はない。
感情はない。
In The Foundation,
...you have
no name and no emotions.
過去はない 未来はない。
You have no past...
and no future.
あるのは 任務。
There is only the mission...
木ノ葉という大木を
目に見えぬ➡
Never forget the will of
The Foundation,
which supports the giant tree known
as the Leaf Village from underground...
地の中より支える
我々 「根」の意思…。
unseen.
決して 忘れるな！
はい…。
I won't.
"Hidden Leaf Hospital"
(ヤマト)お待たせしました。
Sorry to keep you waiting!
遅かったな。
You're late.
いろいろと手間取りまして…。
I got held up with this and that...
まぁ いい…。
Very well...
カカシが待っているぞ。
Kakashi's waiting.
(カカシ)ふ～ん… フフフフフ。
(カカシ)フフ… ん？
"Make-out Paradise Deluxe Edition"
(自来也)来たようだのう。
It looks like they're here...
(綱手)入るぞ カカシ。
We're coming in, Kakashi.
(カカシ)どうぞ。
Please come in.
お久しぶりです… 先輩。
It's been a long time, Senpai!
お前…。
You...
(カカシ)そうか…
ヤマトというのは お前か。
I see. So you're the one
called Yamato, huh?
なるほど。
I get it...
はい。 今日から
カカシ班の隊長代理を務める間は➡
Yes! As of today,
I will be known as Yamato
while I work as the substitute captain
of Team Kakashi.
ヤマトと名乗らせていただきます。
ヤマトねぇ…。
Yamato, huh?
ヤマトを ここに
連れてきたのは➡
I brought him here...
カカシ班の隊長を
務めるにあたり➡
because there's something
I'd really like him to know
ぜひとも 知っておいて
もらいたいことが あるからだ。
since he'll be working as
the captain of Team Kakashi.
そして それが…➡
And that is...
カカシの代理に選ばれた
最大の理由だ。
the biggest reason why he was chosen
as Kakashi's replacement.
ナルト君のことですか？
Is this about Naruto-kun?
そのとおりだ。
Exactly.
(カカシ)ナルトに 九尾の妖狐が
封印されていることは➡
You know that Naruto has
the Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit...
お前も知っているな？
sealed inside him, right?
(ヤマト)はい。
Yes, I do...
(自来也)九尾のチャクラは➡
Sometimes the Nine-Tailed Chakra
leaks out from inside Naruto's body...
時として
ナルトの体内から溢れ出し➡
and takes the form of the Fox Spirit.
妖狐をかたちどることがある。
これを 妖狐の衣と よんでおる。
We call it
the "Nine-Tail's Cloak".
妖狐の衣 ですか…。
The Nine-Tail's Cloak, huh...?
よくあること
なのですか？
Does it happen often?
前回の任務では あった…。
It happened on
our previous mission.
(カカシ)感情の高まりとともに
九尾のチャクラが溢れ出し➡
When his emotions intensified,
the Nine-Tailed Chakra started
to leak out...
全身を覆い…。
it engulfed his body and
became the Nine-Tail's Cloak.
妖狐の衣となった。
(カカシ)２本目の尾ができる寸前に➡
Just before the second tail formed...
自来也様から いただいた札で➡
I somehow managed to suppress
the Chakra
なんとか チャクラを抑え込むことが
できたが…。
with the tag I received
from Jiraiya-sama...
もし あのまま放っておけば
どうなったか…。
But who knows what
would've happened
if things had been left as they were...
そうか… やはり 出てきたか。
I see...
So it appeared just as I thought...
(カカシ)おそらく…
あのチャクラの形状からして➡
Judging from the shape
of the Chakra,
尾は どんどん増えてゆき…
最終的には➡
the number of tails will
probably continue to grow...
and eventually...
９本になる。
there will be nine.
そういうことだのう…。
That's about the size of it...
自来也様は いったい➡
Jiraiya-sama,
how many tails have you seen...?
何本目まで？
ハァ…。
ワシは 今までに二度
死にかけたことがある。
I've come close to dying twice
in my lifetime...
(自来也)一度目は
あばら６本と 両の腕が骨折。
The first time, I broke six ribs
and both arms,
内臓破裂が 数か所。
and several of
my internal organs ruptured...
It was when I was trying to peek
into the women's bath at a hot spring...
温泉で 女風呂をのぞこうとして➡
綱手… お前に思いっきり
やられたときだ。
and you pounded me good, Tsunade.
そして もう一度が…。
The other time was...
ナルトとの修業中➡
during Naruto's training
アイツの九尾チャクラの
４本目の尾を見たときだ。
when I saw the fourth tail
of the Nine-Tailed Chakra.
(サクラ)行ってきます！
I'm off!
≪(サクラ)師匠！
Master!
(シズネ)あ…。
Oh...
(綱手)どうした？
What is it?
You should still have some time
left before you're to assemble.
集合時間には
まだ 間があるはずだが…。
(サクラ)出発前に 師匠にひと言
ご挨拶を と思いまして…。
I wanted to have a few words
before we leave.
そうか…
なら ちょうどよかった。
I see. Then your timing is perfect.
私のほうも
聞いておきたいことがあってな。
There's something
I wanted to ask you.
何です？
What is it?
サイの件だ。
It's about Sai.
(綱手)そうか…。
I see...
もう そんな調子か…。
(サクラ)はい…。
So it's already going badly, huh...?
Yes...
(綱手)しかたない…。
It can't be helped...
とりあえず ナルトは
お前が コントロールしておけ。
For the time being,
you keep Naruto under control.
一応 努力はしてみますけど…。
I'll do what I can, but...
ん？
入れ。
Come in!
《誰だろう…？》
Who's that?
ダンゾウか… 何だ？
Danzo, huh...? What is it?
サイの小隊の隊長には➡
Did you place
a skilled Anbu Black Ops member
as the captain of Sai's unit,
Princess Tsunade?
暗部の優秀な者を
つけていただけましたかな？
綱手姫。
三代目の在任のときから➡
I selected the best man I have.
He's worked since
the Third Hokage's tenure.
いちばんの使い手だった者を
選抜した。
結構…。 ただ ソヤツ➡
Very well...
But I just hope...
he hasn't been tainted by
the teachings of the Third Hokage.
三代目の教えが 染みついて
なければ いいんだがな…。
もめごと嫌いで
腰の引けた三代目の教えが…。
The teachings of the gutless
Third Hokage
who disliked matters of conflict...
(ダンゾウ)あなたの
おじいさまの教えが➡
Just like how the teachings
of your grandfather...
tainted the Third Hokage...
三代目に染みついたようにね…。
とりあえず 安心はしました。
I guess I'm more or less relieved.
(ダンゾウ)
これでゆっくり メシも食える。
Now I can enjoy my meals
without worries.
(ダンゾウ)では…。
Excuse me.
はぁ…。
(サクラ)誰なんです？
Who the hell... was that?
アレ…。
(綱手)昔…
三代目火影の椅子をめぐって➡
A long time ago...
he competed with
the late Sarutobi-Sensei
over the position of the Third Hokage.
亡き 猿飛先生と争った人物だ。
三代目とは違い ガチガチな
合理的思考にもとづく強硬➡
Unlike the Third Hokage,
he's the leader of a hard-line
military faction based on rigid logic...
武闘派路線の主導者で…
サイの上司だ。
and is Sai's superior.
初代火影の孫で 穏健派だった
三代目の教え子の私が➡
He hates me because
I'm the granddaughter of the First Hokage
as well as a student of
the Third Hokage who was a moderate.
嫌いなのさ…。
(シズネ)あの… そろそろ…。
あっ…!!
Umm...
Isn't it about time...?
Oh!
そうか そろそろ時間だろ？
That's right.
Isn't it almost time, Sakura?
サクラ…。
はいっ！ 行ってきます！
Yes, it is...
I'll be going now.
Right!
うむ。
《今度の任務に成功すれば➡
If we succeed in this mission,
we can get one step closer to Sasuke...
サスケに一歩近づける…》
おっし!!
All right!
I'm off!
行ってくるってばよ！
(ヤマト)よし！
Okay...
(ヤマト)では カカシ班…
これより出発する！
Team Kakashi,
will now set out.
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
It begins.
hajimare
A long, long story about you
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
"Tears", "tears".
namidatte namidatte
I want to shed them in happy times
ureshii toki ni nagashitai
So what if I want them to float in pretty puddles?
kirei na mizutamari ukabetai no wa nani
The southern sky,
minami no sora ni
It twinkles.
matataiteiru
From all of the stars meeting.
hoshi no kazu hodo no deai kara
Learning about love, receiving a map.
ai wo manandari chizu wo morattari
Are connected.
tsunagatteku
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
Someday a new page will turn.
itsuka mekuru peeji ni
(自来也)やあ 皆の衆！
秋といえば 芸術の秋 食欲の秋➡
I'm sure it'll be filled with lots of people
kitto takusan no hito ga afureru
そして なんといっても
読書の秋だ！
今日は 話題のベストセラーを
紹介してやろうのぉ！
It begins,
hajimare
A long, long story about you.
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
まずは ご存じ！
ワシの大傑作 『イチャイチャ パラダイス』！
(自来也)全国の男たちのハートを
わしづかみにした➡
Next Episode
How long are you guys going
to argue?
恋愛小説の金字塔！
If this keeps up,
お次は この 『イチャイチャ バイオレンス』！
it will surely affect the way
we carry out our mission.
So here's a suggestion from me.
(自来也)
綿密な取材の上に構築された➡
リアルかつダイナミックな 一大抒情詩！
In order to build unity as a team,
I can toss you guys into
this cell for a full day,
さらに 話題沸騰の最新刊！
『イチャイチャ タクティクス』！
or we can stay at a hot spring inn for
a night. Which would you guys prefer?
(自来也)
すでに 映像化のオファーが続々と…！
I prefer the kind and gentle approach...
コラァ！ エロ仙人！
さっきから 自分の本の紹介
だけじゃねえか！
but I'm not against using fear to
control you guys either when necessary.
やかましいのぉ。
他人の本を紹介しても➡
The Fake Smile
Next Time: "The Fake Smile"
一文の得にも ならんだろうが。
わぁ～…！
Introduction of the Leaf Masterpieces.
何 勝手なこと言って…！
ヌヘヘヘ…。
Hi, everyone.
Autumn makes you think of...
四の五の言わずに みんな買え！
のぉ！
"ART"
art and food.
"FOOD"
And it makes you think of reading
above all else.
"HOBBY - NINJUTSU"
Today I'll be introducing some
hot bestsellers.
First there's my great masterpiece,
I'm sure you all know...
“Make-Out Paradise”!
It's a landmark in romance novels
that grabbed the hearts...
of men all over the land.
Next is “Make Out Violence”.
It's highly realistic and
dynamic lyrical poetry...
that's the result of meticulous research.
And there's my much-talked about
newest volume,
“Make Out Tactics"!
I'm already getting tons of offers
for a film version...
Hey, Pervy Sage!
You've just been introducing
your own books!
You're so annoying.
Introducing someone else's books
won't bring in the money.
What? Stop acting so self--!
Stop arguing and just buy my books,
won't you?